Awesome, awesome.
Welcome back. Now what have you done so far? So far?
You went to the portal of N-Y-C-T-L-C
and then you downloaded one Parquet file from 1 95, right?
And then you upload that file to the data
lake bucket you created.
Let me just show that to you. What you have done so far.
Initially when you ran the script, right,
you asked the cloud engineer team to create a bucket
for you in it lake and that they did that for you, alright?
And then you download the Parquet file
and uploaded that here from your laptop.
So this has three bucket, and then you made use
of a service called as glue.
And specifically you used glue catalog, create a database.
Okay? So assume that upper one is your glue catalog
and is your database.
And within that you're able to create a crawl.
Um, the table, basically you used a glue crawler.
Okay, lemme just write it down here.
And this glue crawler, you pointed that
to the file here in S3 bucket Data lake.
And it crawled over this file.
And, and you asked it to actually create
the table in this database.
And it created a table here.
And as I said, this table and database don't hold data.
Data is in S3 bucket.
So this is an external table which is pointing to this file.
And to view this data in the S3 bucket,
you used a service called Athena.
And in the Athena service you filed a query called us
Select stuff from this, this table from, so Athena went
to the glue catalog, to the glue catalog database
and the table, and then went to the Parquet first data
and showed it in the UI for,
and then you asked the cloud union team
to give access on this database
and this table here to the data analysts as well.
Now, before we proceed, I wanna just, uh,
talk about one thing here.
Now, you may not know about sql, which is absolutely fine.
Okay? We actually, uh, fired, this is Athena console.
We fired Athena Query here, the SQL query.
And we are able to first data here, okay?
Now, if we don't know sql, go
to my SQL skill booster course.
It's a quick course that will actually bring you up
to speed on what SQL is.
So I would highly recommend that.
And also we saw some commands in the cloud shell, right?
We saw ls, we saw,
and we saw sh So these, this terminal is like,
is actually Unix terminal, okay?
Now, you, you may not know about Unix is absolutely fine.
If you don't know about that, go
to the Unix skill booster course.
We'll quickly cover what, uh, UNIX is, what the,
what UNIX commands are typically used by data engineers.
Now let's get back to the discussion.
Now, cloud engineer team has given access
to the analyst, okay?
So you have a data analyst here, business team,
data analyst, and they're able
to acquire a query on Athena, okay?
Now they file a query and they do their
Analysis, they run all sort of queries,
and, um, they feel, yes, there is value in this data,
we need to look at more data.
What they have given us is just one file.
Uh, but on this portal we have data for so many years,
we would at least need data for 2024
and 2025, all the years.
Okay? All these two years we want data.
So that's the next ask from the data analyst into you.
What they also say is that, okay,
in the data we have something called a pickup location id
drop of location id, there are all some IDs.
I wanna know exactly what is a pickup
location, what is the drop location.
And for that, they will ask you to also create a table for
a lookup file.
If you click on this, it'll create a,
it'll download a file on your laptop.
And the contains are right here, location ID
and the borrowers and everything.
So they will want to actually join, join
that data with this data.
Again, I'm talking about join now. Okay?
So this is why you need know sql.
If you wanna sql, so go back to skill booster course on SQL
and come back and then continue.
So using this, when they join to this table,
they can find out the zone, the borrow, all of
that exact pickup, location, pickup drop, all of that.
So the ask is now to also get this file in the data lake
and have a table for that so that they can join this table
with the zone lookup table.
And the second ask here that they want data
for 2025, whatever is available.
If you look at this, we have Datatel November only,
but whatever is available for that year
and for 2024 as well.
So that's your next step. Okay?
And, and before we actually continue,
before you continue the next to the next video, you have
to finish the, the Raid agent Data engineering
with Amazing Q course.
Okay? That course is a prerequisite before we continue.
Okay? That course will teach you how
to actually use agent ai, which we need, in fact,
for our development now.
And I'm sure you have a lot of questions about, you know,
what is agent AI and whether companies allow this.
All of that is covered in that course, the short course.
So make sure you, before you start watching the next video,
you go to that course and only finish that course
and only then come here and continue
because that course already talks about how
to fetch data from this portal to a data lake.
Okay? That course already covers that.
So watch it and then come here.
Now before you go to the next video,
write down in the comment below what is it you have learned.
You know, what story you have learned
because then you write on your own words, the story.
It'll get reinforced in your system, in your system,
and you'll be able to produce that during the interview.
Talk to you soon.